# **Deven Owens**

1162 W Grand Ave Chicago, IL 60642 (773) 645-1289 deven.m3@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/devendraowens

### **SUMMARY**

10 years of experience in help desk, network administration, server administration and cybersecurity. I bring a vast knowledge of many IT disciplines and have recently obtained my Azure Fundamentals and Splunk Core Certified User certifications through self-teaching methods. Looking to join a team where I can leverage my technical and customer service skills to improve a business' security and operational efficiency

# **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Chicago Bachelor of Science, Mathematics and Computer Science December 2014
Minor in Earth and Environmental Sciences

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

CompTIA A+ ce | CompTIA Network+ ce | CompTIA Security+ ce | Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals | Splunk Core Certified User | Cisco Certified Network Associate: Routing and Switching (CCNA RS)

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# IT Engineer at DMG MORI Federal Services, Hoffman Estates, IL

September 2022 — November 2022

70% CMMC compliance project management for DMG MORI Federal Services and 30% supporting DMG MORI USA VMWare ESXi/vSphere instances and Veeam tape backups

- Audited DFARS, ITAR and CUI compliance
- Managed the relationship with the external CMMC compliance vendor and worked with internal employees to develop and put security controls in place following NIST 800-171 and 800-53 guidance
- Performed daily, weekly, and monthly tape backups for DMG MORI North America sites using Veeam Backup and Replication

# IT Infrastructure Engineer at The Scion Group, Chicago, IL

February 2019 — September 2022

System administrator for the company's data and wireless networks, voice networks (VoIP), Windows and Linux servers, storage, email, cybersecurity, virtualization, cloud, and physical security (access control, security cameras, fire alarms)

- Acted as final tier support for critical networking, server, storage, cybersecurity issues
- IT project manager on implementing Microsoft Teams direct routing phones to 127 remote locations
- Utilized PowerShell and the MS Power platform to automate common IT issues
- Designed a scalable SharePoint intranet information architecture which allowed for employees to seamlessly switch to working-from-home and hit record revenues in 2020 during the pandemic
- Implemented Azure Active Directory and organization-wide Multi-Factor Authentication in a hybrid Active Directory environment which helped reduce successful phishing by over 98%
- Performed OS hardening by deploying group policies and utilizing PDQ Deploy using CIS Benchmark recommendations
- Performed security audits of servers, networking equipment, Office 365, and Active Directory

# IT Support Specialist at The Scion Group, Chicago, IL

December 2017 — February 2019

Remote network, application and OS support for 26 off-campus student housing properties and on-site desktop support for an office of 140 employees

- Awarded IT Employee of the Month 5X for outstanding customer service and support
- Built a GIS database to learn what time zone properties were located in using Google Maps which was adapted into the company's hallmark webpage <a href="mailto:thecompany">thesciongroup.com/communities/</a>
- Deployed Mimecast email security and Carbon Black Defender (EDR) organization-wide and primarily responsible for tuning the systems and responding to alerts
- Reconfigured the company's Office 365 distribution groups to use role based access control and wrote a PowerShell script automate the creation of the mail-enabled security groups

# IT Help Desk Analyst at Redfin, Chicago, IL

July 2016 — September 2017

Oversaw the daily IT operations of a newly built call center that rapidly grew from 28 to 170 support agents as well as supporting 2,500 remote employees through phone and email support

- Closed over 450 tickets per month using ITIL methodologies and Zendesk with a 99% customer service rating
- Collaborated with support managers to ensure that productivity and support targets were being achieved with an average NPS of 7
- Created and led the training on Redfin proprietary software to over 80 new employees to optimize on-boarding and reduce common help desk issues in a rapidly expanding office

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

SECURITY TOOLS: EDR/AV: VMWare Carbon Black, SentinelOne, Windows Defender, Wazuh

Identity & Access Management: Active Directory, Azure Active Directory, Jamf Pro, Mobile Iron,

InTune, Dell KACE, Office 365

Email Protection: Office 365 E3/E5, Office 365 Government High, Mimecast, KnowBe4

Logging: Windows Event Viewer, NetFlow, Syslog, SysMon, Splunk SIEM

Experienced with adversary Tactics Techniques and Procedures (TTPs) and how they map to the

MITRE ATT&CK framework

NIST 800 series framework compliance

**NETWORKING:** Sonicwall firewalls, Cisco Catalyst switch management, Ruckus SmartZone and Ubiquiti

Controller Access Point (AP) management, Windows TCP/IP stack, DHCP, DNS, MPLS, OSPF, Cisco

AnyConnect (VPN), Sonicwall NetExtender, RDP, Cisco UCM, Dialpad, ShoreTel/Mitel, 8x8, Microsoft Teams, Snort, Zeek, Wireshark, Fiddler, SMTP and email protection (DKIM, DMARC,

SPF records), Bluetooth

LANGUAGES: Proficient in Powershell, Bash, SQL, MySQL

Familiar with Python, Java, C++

**APPLICATIONS**: Microsoft Office 365, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Visio, Project, Google Workspaces,

VMWare vSphere/ESXi, Scale Computing H3, Windows Hyper-V, N-Able, Confluence, JIRA, Slack, ZenDesk, AutoTask, SalesForce, SharePoint, Google Sites, SQL, Veeam Backup, SysInternals,

Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)

OPERATING SYSTEMS: Windows XP-11; Mac OS X, Linux OS (Ubuntu, CentOS, Kali), Windows Server 2008R2-2019;

Android, Apple iOS, Raspbian, Cisco IOS, FortiOS, SonicOS

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULARS**

TryHackMe Top 5% <a href="https://tryhackme.com/p/ownsdev">https://tryhackme.com/p/ownsdev</a>
Producer of The Mindful Business Security Show podcast
Black Hills Information Security SOC Core Skills course
1st place TryHackMe Advent of Cyber CTF
Blue Team Con Attendee

March 2023 January 2023 - Present November 2022 November 2022 August 2022